Guide to the Miner Searle Bates Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings, Series VI
  - Related to Major Works
    - "The Theology of American Missionaries in China" (Paper presented at 1972 Cuernavaca Conference on American Missionaries in China and America and included as chapter in The Missionary Enterprise in China and America,1974, Ed. by John K. Fairbank)- Handwritten drafts (Box 93, Folder 753)
    - "The Theology of American Missionaries in China" Typescript draft of Cuernavaca paper, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 754)
    - "The Theology of American Missionaries in China" Paper as presented at Cuernavaca, 1972 (Box 93, Folder 755)
    - "The Theology of American Missionaries in China": Drafts for chapter in Fairbank book, 1972-1973 (Box 93, Folder 756)
- Course Related Materials, 1952-1965, n.d.; Series VII
  The materials of Series VII are arranged by course title with the additional subheadings as required.
  - Christian Ethics 394/494: Christianity and Communism: Handouts, exams, 1952-1965, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 757)
  - Christian Ethics 394/494: Bates' notes, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 758)
  - Christian Ethics 394/494: Source materials, bibliographies, 1950-1963, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 759)
  - Missions 221: The World Christian Mission in History, to 1800, 1952-1963, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 760)
  - Missions 222: The World Christian Mission in History, 1800 to present, 1951-1958, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 761)
  - Missions 230: Missions and the Younger Churches Today, 1957-1959 (Box 94, Folder 762)
  - Missions 231/232: The Christian Church and World Issues: Handouts, 1955-1962, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 763)
  - Missions 231/232: Bates' notes, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 764)
  - Missions 231/232: Source materials, 1948-1964, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 765-766)
  - Missions 238 (Church and Community 206): Christianity in Social Change and Cultural Conflict, 1954 (Box 95, Folder 767)
  - Missions 258: Church and State in Latin America, 1952 (Box 95, Folder 768)
  - Missions 441: Principles and Practice of the World Mission of Christianity: Handouts, 1957-1959 (Box 95, Folder 769)
  - Missions 441: Bates' notes, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 770)
  - Missions 441: Source materials, 1942-1956, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 771)
  - Missions 446: The Life and Work of the Younger Churches: Handouts, 1958. 1962, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 772)
  - Missions 446: Bates' notes, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 772)
  - Missions 446: Source materials, 1957-1964, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 773)
  - Theology 251/351: The World and the Church: Handouts, 1954-1964, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 774-776)
  - Theology 251/351: Communications between instructors of course, 1956-1963, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 777-778)
  - Theology 251/351: Bates' notes, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 779)
  - Theology 251/351: Questionnaire on Roman Catholic church, ca. 1957 (Box 95, Folder 780)
  - Theology 251/351: Source material, 1956-1959 (Box 96, Folder 781)
  - Other courses at Union Theological Seminary, 1950-1952, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 782)
  - Program of Advanced Religious Studies at Union Theological Seminary (PARS): General, 1955-1965, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 783-784)
  - Program of Advanced Religious Studies at Union Theological Seminary (PARS): Correspondence, 1954, 1959, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 785-786)
  - Program of Advanced Religious Studies at Union Theological Seminary (PARS): Courses, 1963-1965, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 787)
  - Columbia University Seminar on Modern East Asia, 1959 (Box 96, Folder 788)
  - Columbia University, East Asian Institute, 1952, 1953 (Box 96, Folder 789)
  - Lecture notes for unidentified course: "Introductory lecture"; "Africa in Christian Perspective" (Box 97, Folder 790)
  - Lecture notes for unidentified course: "Asia in Christian Perspective" (Box 97, Folder 791)
  - Lecture notes for unidentified course: "Europe in Christian Perspective" (Box 97, Folder 792)
  - Lecture notes for unidentified course: "Re. Latin America (Box 97, Folder 793)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, Series VIII
  The material of Series VIII is chronologically arranged within the following sections:
  Memorabilia/ biographical documentation
  Address books, cards
  Diaries, memo books
  Medical records
  Passports, military passes, identification certificates
  Related to family members
  School notebooks
  Sections of photographs and postcards are informally arranged.
  - Memorabilia/ biographical documentation
    - Certified copy of birth record, 1916 (Box 126, Folder 1133)
    - Army discharge, 1918 (Box 126, Folder 1133)
    - Hiram College years, 1914-1915, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 1134)
    - St. John's College, Oxford, 1916-1920 (Box 126, Folder 1135)
    - YMCA work, Mesopotamia, 1917-1918 (Box 126, Folder 1136)
    - Miscellaneous, incl. Bates' participation in Tokyo war crimes trials--transcript of testimony before International Military Tribunal for the Far East (1946), 1921-1948 (Box 126, Folder 1137)
    - Misc., 1950-1978, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 1138-1141)
    - Artifacts, 1922, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 1142)
    - Chinese language material, n.d. (Box 126, Folder 1143)
  - Address books, cards
    - Of MSB (Box 127, Folder 1144)
  - Diaries, memo books
    - Of MSB, 1917,1918, 1944-1978 (Box 127, Folder 1145-1149)
  - Medical records
    - Sampling of medical records, 1941-1978 (Box 128, Folder 1150)
  - Passports, military passes, identification certificates
    - Of MSB, 1916-1968 (Box 128, Folder 1151)
  - Material related to family members
    - Misc., 1926-1978, n.d. (Box 128, Folder 1153)
  - Notebooks
    - School notes, 1910,1911, n.d. (Box 128, Folder 1154-1155)
  - Photographs
    - M.S. Bates, 1917,1950, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 1156)
    - Family (Box 129, Folder 1157)
    - Hiram College 1911 (?), 1916 (Box 129, Folder 1158)
    - China scenes and groups (Box 129, Folder 1159)
    - Miscellaneous individuals (Box 129, Folder 1160)
    - Miscellaneous scenes and groups (Box 129, Folder 1161)